得畲兄，這幾天問了相關的朋友，只有直接在大陸開始，大陸的公司，在大陸設立R&D, 我們才能安全，可靠進行這個Start up! 1）能夠直接將所有technical guys 的股權或 options 直接落到各位，不用代持，2）tools will not be issue, directly local government supports, 3) without going through 3rd countries or place to set up Taiwan subsidiary, which is nearly total difficult since Taiwan gov must ensure no mainland investment involved, 4) future IP will be total legal within mainland China, instead if developing done in Taiwan, Taiwan gov might ban or not permit such IP to go to mainland China. Or charge people involved. So conclusion is startup in mainland in day one! Please take a deep consideration for such issue, thank you! And let discuss more